mate1.com 2013-06-21

# Best Online Dating Site - Free Local Personals & Local Singles | Mate1

Thank You for visiting the Mate1® website located at www.mate1.com (the "Site"). The Site is an Internet property of Mate1.com Inc. ("Company," "We," "Our" or "Us"). You ("You" or "Your") agree to this Mate1.com® Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy"), in its entirety, when You: (a) access or use the Site; (b) become a Member; and/or (c) use the Service. Capitalized terms not defined herein shall have the meaning set forth in the Mate1.com® Terms and Conditions ("Terms and Conditions"). **If You do not agree to this Privacy Policy in its entirety, You are not authorized to use the Site and/or Service in any manner or form whatsoever.**

Our mission is to provide a secure meeting place where Members can connect privately and anonymously. It is up to You to decide if and when to reveal Your identity to another Member or to Meet-Up in person.

In drafting this Privacy Policy, We seek to give Our Members' peace of mind about Our privacy practices. The practices outlined herein represent Our effort to allow You to safeguard the confidentiality of Your personal information, while also protecting the interests of Company. 

Mate1.com Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html#phonegap=external) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, www.mate1.com and does not cover mobile applications.

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at privacy@mate1.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint#phonegap=external).

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, through notice via a link posted on the home page of the Site, and provided that such changes shall only apply to information gathered on or after the date of such changes. In the event that We do decide to make material changes regarding how We use personal information previously collected from You, You will be notified of such changes via email. Your continued use of the Site, Service and/or continued receipt of Company marketing messages after posting of the Privacy Policy change on the Site, or receipt of a Privacy Policy change notification e-mail, as applicable, constitutes an affirmative acknowledgement and acceptance by You of the modified Privacy Policy.

If You have suggestions as to how We might improve this Privacy Policy, or any aspect of the Site, please contact Us [here](http://www.mate1.com/nw/feedback/suggestions) or at [privacy@mate1.com](mailto:privacy@mate1.com).

If You are a resident of the State of California and would like to know how Your “personal information” (as defined in the Shine the Light Law, Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.83) is shared with third parties by Us, what categories of personal information that We have shared with third parties in the preceding year, as well as the names and addresses of those third parties, please contact Us at: [privacy@mate1.com](mailto:privacy@mate1.com).

If You are a resident of the State of California and would like to opt-out from the disclosure of Your personal information to any third-party for marketing purposes, please contact Us at [privacy@mate1.com](mailto:privacy@mate1.com). Please be advised that where California residents opt-out from permitting their personal information to be shared, such individuals may still receive selected offers directly from Us, in accordance with applicable law.

* ### Information Requested from Members

When You register to use the Service, as either a Guest Member or Full Member, You will be asked for some general identifying information, as well as demographic, personal and billing information, which will enable Us to better provide You with the Service. The registration data that You must supply on the Application in order to obtain access to the Service may include, without limitation, depending on the applicable Membership level requested: (a) Your full name; (b) e-mail address; (c) mailing address; (d) daytime, evening and/or cellular telephone numbers; (e) date of birth; (f) gender; (g) credit card information, checking account information, PayPal® account information or Apple® Store account information (depending on Your preferred method of payment); (h) optional Profile information such as ethnic background, appearance, features, religion, income range, occupation, sexual preference/lifestyle information; (i) any other information You choose to provide, such as Your personal interests, preferences and general indications of the type of partner You are looking for through use of the Service; and/or (j) any other information requested on the Application. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, item (g) in the preceding sentence shall be referred to as "Payment Information." 

If You choose to become a Full Member, We may collect Your Payment Information. Payment Information is gathered and processed through Our own secure server or through a third-party billing website, and encrypted via a secure server to ensure that others cannot access it. To the extent that Company collects Your Payment Information, if ever, We will use the information solely to process and complete any transaction(s) that You request. By submitting credit card information to Us, if applicable, You authorize Company to periodically verify that Your credit card account continues to be a valid and active one by charging, and thereafter immediately crediting, a small sum to the card. Such verification may be conducted through a third-party and, in that case, Company would share Your specific credit card information with this third-party for verification purposes. Apart from said uses, We will not share Your Payment Information with any third-parties without Your prior informed consent unless We are compelled to disclose such information to a governmental entity in response to a valid government-issued subpoena, search warrant or court order seeking such information and which complies with applicable local or federal law. Notwithstanding the foregoing, Company reserves the right to share with third-parties the fact that We have Payment Information on file for specific Members, but We will not share Your specific Payment Information with third-parties without Your prior informed consent.

_For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "PayPal®" shall mean PayPal, Inc. Please be advised that Company is not in any way affiliated with PayPal®, and the Site and Service are neither endorsed, nor sponsored, by PayPal®. PayPal® is a registered trademark of PayPal, Inc._

_For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Apple®" shall mean Apple Inc. Please be advised that Company is not in any way affiliated with Apple®, and the Site and Service are neither endorsed, nor sponsored, by Apple®. Apple® is a registered trademark of Apple Inc._

* ### Public Information

Public information is Profile information that You enter on the Site when filling out Your Profile that You make available for viewing by other Members (but not non-Member visitors). During the registration process, You will be asked to create a "Mini Profile." The Mini Profile consists of personal but non-identifying information (i.e. Your relationship status, height, body type, ethnicity, religion, personal habits, etc). Once You become a registered Member of the Site, You will have the option of adding further text, photos and a voice recording to Your Profile. This public Profile information, collectively known within the Site as Your "Profile," is not linked to Your personal information in any way that can be seen by other Members of, or visitors to, the Site, unless You include personally identifying information in the portions of Your Profile that You fill-out Yourself. If You upload a photograph of Yourself to Your Profile, Your Profile may become personally identifiable to the extent other Members can match Your photograph with Your Profile information.

Please be advised that if You make Your Profile available on the Site, other Members and Members of other websites owned and/or operated by Company may be able to reach You via e-mail using the Company-operated e-mail interface, as well as other Interactive Services made available to Members; provided, however, that Company will not share Your personal e-mail address with such Members. These e-mails, IMs, chat, text and other Interactive Services-based communications contain comments, opinions, information and other content that is provided directly by Members. Company shall have no obligation and incur no liability to You or any other Members in connection with any such comments, opinions, information and/or other content communicated via the Interactive Services.

* ### Interactive Services

If You comment on a blog post or other Interactive Services forum, or otherwise provide Feedback and/or Content (as those terms are defined in the Terms and Conditions) by and through the Interactive Services, You should be aware that any personally identifiable information that You submit there can be read, collected or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send You unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information that You choose to submit in and/or through these forums. _To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at privacy@mate1.com_. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

* ### Use of Member Personal Information

We reserve the right to share, sell, rent, lease and/or otherwise distribute any and all personal information (other than Payment Information), on an aggregate and non-aggregate basis, with/to any third-party for any and all uses permitted by this Privacy Policy and applicable law. These third parties may include, but shall not be limited to: (a) providers of direct marketing services and applications, including lookup and reference, data enhancement, suppression and validation; (b) e-mail marketers; (c) telemarketers (where and to the extent permitted by applicable law); (d) SMS text-based marketers (where and to the extent permitted by applicable law); and (e) direct marketers.

By registering for the Service, You specifically agree to receive communications from Us to the email address that You provide when registering including, but not limited to: notifications of emails and instant messages that You have received from other Members on the Site and from Members of other websites owned and/or operated by Company, relevant Profiles that match Your search criteria, tips and advice related to the Service, updates regarding the Service, special promotions and offers and notices of changes to the Site and/or the Agreement. In addition, by submitting Your e-mail address at the Site, You agree to receive e-mail marketing from Us and Our third-party advertisers. Such e-mail communications may contain commercial messaging, such as advertisements and special offers from Us and Our third party marketing affiliates. We may use tracking technologies that enables Us to track Your usage of the e-mail messages that We send You, including whether the e-mail message was opened and what links were clicked. The Site provides You with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving some types of communications from Us by changing Your email-settings on the page entitled "Your Settings." If You do not opt-out of receiving such notices, they will be sent to You automatically, at Our discretion. 

By submitting Your telephone number at the Site, You agree that such act constitutes a purchase, an inquiry and/or an application for purposes of the Amended Telemarketing Sales Rule, 16 CFR §310 et seq. (the "ATSR"). With respect to the ATSR, and notwithstanding that Your telephone number may be listed on the Federal Trade Commission's Do-Not-Call List, Company retains the right to contact You via telemarketing in accordance with the terms of the ATSR.

Further, You agree that by submitting Your personal information at the Site, You agree to receive mobile marketing including, but not limited to, text-message based marketing, from Us (where, and to the extent that, such marketing is permitted by applicable law). As such, notwithstanding that Your mobile telephone number may be listed on state and/or federal Do-Not-Call registries, We retain the right to contact You via text-message based marketing in accordance with applicable state and federal law.

Your general demographic information is used to personalize Your experience with the Service and on the Site and on other websites owned and/or operated by Company; to compose Your personal Profile; to allow other Members of the Site and Members of other websites owned and/or operated by Company to find You through a search of the Site or other websites owned and/or operated by Company; and to deliver targeted advertising and promotional offers to You. By purchasing, registering for or agreeing to receive communication about products or services offered or promoted by third parties on the Site, or electing to participate in contests, sweepstakes or other programs offered or promoted by third parties on the Site, You consent to Our providing Your personal information (other than Payment Information) to those third parties. 

We may enter into promotional relationships with other companies in which We display their brand name or trademarks on pages of the Site or in e-mails delivered to You by Us. These companies are known as "Co-Branded Companies" and the pages on which their branding appears are known as "Co-Branded Pages." If You submit information on a Co-Branded Page, on a page accessed by clicking on a link on a Co-Branded Page or if You choose to receive information, products or services from a Co-Branded Company on a page on the Site, then We may share Your personal information with the applicable Co-Branded Company. The information that We share with a Co-Branded Company may include any personal information that You have entered on the Site, but will NOT include any Payment Information without Your explicit permission. Co-Branded Companies may use Your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies, over which We have no control. Additionally, You agree that We may use and disclose all such information submitted to such Co-Branded Companies in the same manner in which We are entitled to use and disclose any other information You submit to Us.

Company is informed and believes that some Co-Branded Pages may contain an action tag (also known as a Web Beacon or a 1pixel .gif file) that a third party may use to read cookies that it, or its clients, may have placed on Your browser at other websites before Your visit to the Site. Company understands that this technology is used to measure the effectiveness of advertisements on other websites that promote these Co-Branded Pages . Company is informed and believes that these third parties may use the information collected through this technology to learn more about Your visits to this Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to You. These third parties have represented to Company that, unless You are otherwise notified, they do not use Your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number, and do not link Your online actions to any information that can be used to identify or contact You. Because these are based on representations made by the Co-Branded Companies, Company advises You to seek assurances Yourself that the above representations by the Co-Branded Companies are accurate. Company cannot be held accountable for the accuracy of the above representations made by the Co-Branded Companies.

When you use or connect to a Company website or download a Company mobile app by or through a Third Party Platform, such as Facebook or other social networking site, you allow us to access and/or collect certain information from your Third Party Platform profile/account (such as your Facebook account) or via any cookies placed on your device by such Third Party Platform as permitted by the terms of the agreement and your privacy settings with the Third Party Platform. We will share such information with the Third Party Platform for their use as permitted by the terms of the agreement and your privacy setting with the Third Party Platform.

We will share some of the information we collect from you upon install of the mobile app with vendors and other service providers who are engaged by or working with us in connection with the operation of the services we provide to you and/or for analytics purposes which may require the reproduction and display of such information in an aggregated and anonymized manner such that will not in any way identify you.

Company reserves the right to share Your personal information: (i) where You are in violation of this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms and Conditions; (ii) where Company determines, in its sole discretion, that such disclosure is necessary to protect the rights of Company and/or a third party, or necessary to protect Company from liability of any kind; (iii) if the information is subpoenaed; provided, however, that, where permitted by applicable law, We shall provide You with e-mail notice, and opportunity to challenge the subpoena, prior to disclosure of any Personal Information pursuant to a subpoena; or (iv) if Company is sold, merged or acquired; provided, however, that if Company is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on the Site of any change in ownership or uses of Your personal information, as well as any choices that You may have regarding use of Your personal information. The aforementioned includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection purposes.

* ### Non-Personal Information Gathered Automatically from Visitors

We collect data directly from Site visitors' computers. This non-personal information does not disclose any personal information about You. This non-personal information includes Your IP address, browser type and browser settings. We use Your IP address (the numeric code that identifies Your individual computer) to avoid fraudulent registrations, help Us maintain the Site and Service and identify problems with Our server. Your IP address does not disclose any personally revealing information about You. Information that We may obtain regarding Your browser and browser settings enables Us to ensure that the Site's technical features are available to be used by You. 

We use cookies to identify traffic that comes through advertising and to improve user experience. Cookies are small pieces of information that a website places on Your computer's hard drive to enable that website to recognize You and to save You the trouble of re-entering some basic information when You revisit the website. To find out more about cookies, please visit www.cookiecentral.com. From time to time, Company may allow third party entities that display advertisements on some of the Site's pages to place their cookies on Your computer. These third party entities' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, which We have no control over. We do not allow other companies to access cookies placed by Us. The use of cookies is a very common practice on the Internet. If You are uncomfortable with the use of cookies on the Site, You can disable all cookies by adjusting the settings associated with Your Internet browser. Even in the case where a Member rejects a cookie, he or she may still use the Site; provided, however, that certain functions of the Service may be impaired or rendered inoperable if the use of cookies is disabled.

We share non-personal information about Your activity at the Site with Lotame Solutions, Inc. ("Lotame") for the purpose of tailoring, analyzing and reporting on advertising that You see. Lotame may use cookies, web beacons and/or other technology to tailor the advertisements that You see on the Site and at other websites that You may visit. For more information about the information that is collected and used by Lotame, or to opt-out of Lotame's use of this information, please see Lotame's privacy policy at [http://www.lotame.com/legal](http://www.lotame.com/legal#phonegap=external).

* ### Opt-Out/Unsubscribe

During registration and/or when You otherwise submit personal information to Us at or through the Site, You have opted-in and authorized Us to share Your personal information with third-parties for marketing purposes. To stop receiving future communications from Company, please [Click Here](http://www.mate1.com/nw/index#~/ref/page/profile/settings?section=email). To opt-out of having Your information shared with third-parties, please [Click Here](http://www.mate1.com/nw/index#~/ref/page/profile/settings?section=email). To change Your e-mail preferences, You can access the page "Your Settings" on the Site and follow the instructions there, click on the "Deactivate" link located at the bottom of the applicable e-mail or by send Us mail to the following postal address making sure to indicate which promotional emails You wish to opt out of: 

Mate1.com Inc  
4200 St. Laurent Blvd. Ste 550  
Montreal, QC H2W 2R2  

Please note that changing Your preferences regarding the receipt of marketing communications from Us will not prevent other companies with which We already have shared Your information, including third party advertisers, from continuing to provide You with marketing offers. When contacted by these companies, You should notify them directly of Your choices regarding their use and sharing of Your information. In addition, please note that if You subsequently sign up for another one of Our product or service offerings, You will need to reconfirm any information sharing preferences that You have previously changed. 

Notwithstanding the foregoing, We may continue to contact You for the purpose of communicating information relating to Your use of the Site and Service, general information regarding Company and to respond to any inquiry or request made by You.

You may "opt out" of the collection of your information by the mobile app tracking services of Has Offers inc., for third party analytics purposes by following the directions provided by our third party analytics vendor located at http://www.mobileapptracking.com/privacy-policy/. If you "opt out" with our third party analytics provider, that action is specific to the information we collect specifically for that provider, and does not limit our ability to collect information from you, under the terms of this privacy policy, for other vendors.

* ### Managing or Removing Your Personal Information

We keep the information that You have given Us for as long as You are a Member. At Your request, We will inform You of what information We have on file for You. In addition, at Your request, We will remove information that You have provided to us, or that We have collected. You can always verify or request the removal of the personally identifiable information that We have collected, or change Your registration information, by visiting the appropriate subsection of Your Profile or Your account settings. You may make changes to Your Profile, suspend Your account or remove Your account completely at any time through the automated tools provided in Your settings, or by contacting customer support.

* ### Security

All collected information is stored in a technically and physically secure environment. When Our registration/application process asks Members to enter sensitive information (such as Payment Information, etc.), and when We store and transmit such sensitive information, that information is encrypted and protected with SSL encryption software. While We use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, We also do everything in Our power to protect all user information both online and off-line.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while We strive to protect Your personal information, We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that You transmit to us, and You do so at Your own risk. Once We receive Your transmission, We make reasonable efforts to ensure its security on Our systems. Access to this information is strictly limited, and not accessible to the public. All of Our Members' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in Our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example a customer service representative) are granted access to personal information. Our employees are dedicated to ensuring the security and privacy of all Member information. Employees not adhering to Our firm policies are subject to disciplinary action. In compliance with applicable law, We shall notify You and any applicable regulatory agencies in the event that We learn of an information security breach with respect to Your personal information. You will be notified via e-mail in the event of such a breach. Please be advised that notice may be delayed in order to address the needs of law enforcement, determine the scope of network damage and to engage in remedial measures.

* ### Minors

No information should be submitted to, or posted at, the Site by visitors under eighteen (18) years of age. Persons under eighteen (18) years of age are not permitted to access the Site or use the Service and We do not knowingly collect personal information from such individuals. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate and monitor the interactive activities of their children.

* ### Monitoring Site Activity

Our Members communicate with each other through the Interactive Services and other Site interface features. While We do not generally censor or monitor Members' private exchanges, We reserve the right to do so if We suspect Members of being underage or of using the Service in violation of the Terms and Conditions or this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to edit, delete, remove or withhold any communication transmitted by and through the Site.

* ### Third Party Websites

the site may contain links to other third-party owned and/or operated websites. company is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. in some cases, you may be able to make a purchase through one of their third-party websites. in these instances, you may be required to provide certain information, such as a credit card number, to register or complete a transaction at such website. these third-party websites have separate privacy and data collection practices and company has no responsibility or liability relating to them.

* ### Affiliates

When You register to become an Affiliate of the Site, You will be asked for contact information and information related to Your website and/or other marketing venues/methods. Your information will only be used by internal staff and will never be shared with any external entity without Your consent, other than Our advisors and representatives, unless We are required to do so by operation of law. Your information will be used to secure Your approval as an Affiliate, to facilitate communication between You and Company and to send You payment, based on Your performance as an Affiliate.

* ### Canadian Laws Apply

Company is located in Canada. If You are visiting the Site from outside Canada, You are on notice that Your information may be transferred to, stored and processed in Canada. The data protection and other laws of Canada and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in Your country. Nous avons demande que cette convention ainsi que tous les documents qui s'y rattachent soient rediges en anglais.
